<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Haotian Fan</title>
    <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Haotian Fan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 13:56:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://flyfov.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EMG signal classification based on machine learning</title>
      <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/emg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/emg/</guid>
      <description>Intro Electromyogram (EMG) signal is very popular in hand gesture analysis, prostheses control technologies. The EMG signal is generated by the human muscles and can be collected using censors, different movements of our muscles can result in different features of EMG signal, like frequency and amplitude. However, the classification of EMG signal is not an easy job due to mainly two reasons. Firstly, the noisy behaviors of EMG signal can influence the recognize process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Web Page of Coronavirus out break</title>
      <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/coronavirus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/coronavirus/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The project our team is working on is an interactive web page based on the recent Corona Virus outbreak, where users can learn about changes in air quality, human flow and so on before and after the outbreak,so that they are able to schedule their travel plans during the outbreak. During this gradually relieving-period, the covering capabilities of different regions vary from each other. So we used data on the number of people diagnosed in different areas to simulate the virus content(numbers) and realize part of data visualization to remind users keep far away from areas where they are still at risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UAV communication deploy optimization based on reinforcement learning</title>
      <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/dronerouteopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/dronerouteopt/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs), popularly known as drones, is rapidly growing in a wide range of wireless networking applications. The advancement in communication, networking, computation, and sensing technologies has attracted researchers, hobbyist, and investors to deploy mini UAVs due to their enormous applications. Drones have boundless viable applications as well due to its small size and capability to fly without an on-board pilot such as in agriculture, photography, surveillance, and numerous public services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of electromagnetic propagation on the ocean</title>
      <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/mcm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/mcm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The electromagnetic wave can spread by reflecting from ionosphere and ocean, but the attenuation during this process limited the communication effect. In this paper, we discussed the situation that the electromagnetic wave propagation on the ocean.
Based on the Fresnel law and the calculation formula of transmission loss for shortwave skywave communication, we set up a model to discuss the calculation of the attenuation of calm ocean surface and the signal strength after a hopping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face recognition system acclerated by FPGA</title>
      <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/face_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/face_recognition/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project using a MCU combined with FPGA to achieve face recognition in real time. FPGA is much more fast in data loads and processing, which can acclerate the face recognition process. We use CNN as the traning method to predict the result. The projct got a nation second prize in National Fpga contest.   Certification </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wild animal inspection system based on LoRa and UAV</title>
      <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/uav_inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/uav_inspection/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Traditional wild animal inspection system uses jeeps driving around the protection zone, which costs huge amounts of human resoureces and money. To optimize the wild animal inspection efficency and lower the cost of the procdure, we came up with a mthod which combines UAV and LoRa, which is a kind of long range communication device. We use drones to replace the jeeps and design the flying trail to cover the protection area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple digital balance system</title>
      <link>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 13:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://flyfov.github.io/projects/balance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I took part in china national electronic contest, and ranked first among hundreds of teams in question D. The sponsor of the match is Texas Instruments. The contest requires us to design a digital balance system within four days and three nights. Our team has three members and I was responsible for software design. I only slept totally seven hours in four days to finish this project. I designed a program which contains analog to digital convertor, display unit using an LCD, temperature drift rectifies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>